Not long after
얼마 지나지 않아
Nandu City fell
남도성이 함락되었습니다
You're still here
왜 아직도 여기 있소
I've always been here
한시도 떠난 적 없어요
No matter what the outcome
결과가 어떻든
I will face it together with Your Majesty
폐하와 함께 맞이하겠습니다
Great Xuan's accumulation over decades
선나라가 수십 년 쌓아온 모든 것이
Now destroyed in one fire
한순간에 불타버렸으니
It is my fault
모두 짐의 잘못이오
Since ancient times, rulers die with their state
예로부터 군왕은 사직과 함께 죽는 법
As long as I am here
짐이 아직 살아 있는 한
Great Xuan will not be humiliated
선나라는 아무도 짓밟을 수 없소
Your Majesty still has a sword
폐하께는 아직 검이 있고
Has heroic spirit
영웅의 기개가 있으며
And me
그리고 제가 있습니다
They say Chen and Sikong
모두들 진가와 사공가가
Rule the realm together
천하를 함께 다스린다고 했는데
Now
지금은
It is Chen and Sikong
진가와 사공가가
Facing survival and destruction together
함께 존망을 맞이하네요
Arm me
짐에게 갑옷을 입혀주시오
Yes
예
Miss Chen
진 낭자
What a coincidence
참으로 우연입니다
I am here on my granduncle's orders
저는 종조부의 명을 받들어
To report to His Majesty
폐하께 아뢸 것이 있어서 왔습니다
Miss Chen
진 낭자
My benefits
내가 얻는 게
Aren't they a bit lacking?
너무 적지 않은가?
A mutually beneficial matter
서로 이득을 주고받는 일인데
What else does Your Highness want?
전하께서는 또 무엇을 더 바라시나요?
My friendship
저의 우정을
Does Your Highness dare to want it?
감히 받을 수 있겠나요
You traitor
감히 가문을 배신하려고 해?
Look at our ancestors
조상님들 앞에서
Think about what you've done
네가 저지른 일을 돌이켜 봐라
Do you still know your surname?
네 성씨를 기억이나 하느냐?
Chen
진 씨입니다
This is for Your Highness
이건 전하에게나
For the Chen family
진가에게나
And for the realm
천하에나
The best outcome
가장 좋은 결말입니다
Are you afraid?
안 두렵소?
With Your Majesty here
폐하께서 계시기에
I'm not afraid
두렵지 않습니다
Beat the drums for me
짐을 위해 북을 울려라!
I will protect Great Xuan
나는 선나라를 지킬 것이다
Until the end
마지막 순간까지
Corpses fill the palace
시신이 궁성을 메우고
Blood fills the streets
피가 거리를 가득 채웠습니다
This is the integrity Xuan Kingdom lacked for decades
이는 선국이 수십 년 늦게 되찾은 기개였습니다
The capital's sun
도성의 태양이
Has set
저물었습니다